{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": {
        "theme": [
          {
            "Question": "In which period drama does the family name Crawley feature?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Downton Abbey",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Bridgerton",
              "Poldark",
              "The Crown"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The family name Crawley is central to the narrative of 'Downton Abbey,' a British historical drama set in the early 20th century."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who played the lead role in the TV series 'Poldark'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Aidan Turner",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Colin Firth",
              "Tom Hiddleston",
              "Richard Madden"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Aidan Turner portrayed the protagonist, Ross Poldark, in the BBC adaptation of the historical novels by Winston Graham."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which historical event sets the backdrop for 'Victoria'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Victorian Era",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "World War I",
              "French Revolution",
              "Russian Revolution"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The series 'Victoria' is set during the Victorian Era, spanning Queen Victoria's reign from 1837 to 1901."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What time period does 'Peaky Blinders' primarily take place in?",
            "TrueAnswer": "1920s",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "19th Century",
              "1940s",
              "18th Century"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Peaky Blinders' is predominantly set in the aftermath of World War I, capturing the volatile 1920s in Birmingham, England."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which period drama features the fictional town of Cranford?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Cranford",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "The Knick",
              "Mad Men",
              "Versailles"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Cranford' is a British television series adapted from the works of Elizabeth Gaskell, depicting the small rural town in the 1840s."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the famous playwright featured in the TV series 'Shakespeare & Hathaway: Private Investigators'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "William Shakespeare",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Oscar Wilde",
              "George Bernard Shaw",
              "Arthur Miller"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The show incorporates themes and references to the renowned works of William Shakespeare, intertwining mysteries with the playwright's legacy."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Where is the setting for the TV series 'Miss Fisher's Murder Mysteries'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "1920s Melbourne",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "18th Century London",
              "1950s New York",
              "19th Century Paris"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Miss Fisher's Murder Mysteries' unfolds in the vibrant and diverse city of Melbourne during the glamorous 1920s era."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which royal family is central to the storyline of 'The Crown'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "House of Windsor",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "House of Tudor",
              "House of Stuart",
              "House of Hanover"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Crown' revolves around the House of Windsor, depicting key events and intricate dynamics within the British monarchy."
          },
          {
            "Question": "In 'Anne with an E', which Canadian province is the setting for the story?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Prince Edward Island",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Nova Scotia",
              "Manitoba",
              "Alberta"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Anne with an E' is set mainly in the picturesque landscapes of Prince Edward Island, capturing the beauty of rural Canada."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the admired consort in the historical drama 'The Spanish Princess'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Catherine of Aragon",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Anne Boleyn",
              "Mary, Queen of Scots",
              "Elizabeth I"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Spanish Princess' narrates the journey of Catherine of Aragon, the captivating first wife of King Henry VIII."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which period drama series follows the lives of the Bridgerton family?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Bridgerton",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Spartacus",
              "Vikings",
              "The Last Kingdom"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The opulent world of 'Bridgerton' unveils the romantic entanglements and societal intrigues of the esteemed Bridgerton family in Regency-era London."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who leads the rebellion in the TV series 'Turn: Washington's Spies'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Abraham Woodhull",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Alexander Hamilton",
              "Thomas Jefferson",
              "Benjamin Franklin"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The character Abraham Woodhull, also known as Samuel Culper, oversees a network of spies during the American Revolutionary War in 'Turn: Washington's Spies.'"
          },
          {
            "Question": "What historical event serves as the backdrop for 'The White Queen'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Wars of the Roses",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Hundred Years' War",
              "English Civil War",
              "The Crusades"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The White Queen' delves into the tumultuous Wars of the Roses, a riveting period of political upheaval and noble rivalries in medieval England."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which historical figure is the center of the TV series 'The Borgias'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Rodrigo Borgia",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Leonardo da Vinci",
              "Michelangelo",
              "Niccolò Machiavelli"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Borgias' revolves around the ambitious and controversial figure of Rodrigo Borgia, who ascends to become Pope Alexander VI during the Renaissance era."
          },
          {
            "Question": "In 'Mr. Selfridge', what iconic department store does Harry Selfridge establish?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Selfridges",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Macy's",
              "Harrods",
              "Bloomingdale's"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The series portrays Harry Gordon Selfridge's visionary creation of the renowned Selfridges department store in London, shaping modern retail concepts."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which historical period does the TV series 'Harlots' primarily explore?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Georgian Era",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Elizabethan Era",
              "Renaissance",
              "Edwardian Era"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Harlots' delves into the scandalous underworld of 18th-century London, offering a gritty portrayal of the Georgian Era's societal complexities."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which literary classic is the source material for the TV adaptation 'North & South'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Elizabeth Gaskell's Novel",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Jane Austen's Novel",
              "Charlotte Brontë's Novel",
              "Emily Brontë's Novel"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'North & South' is adapted from Elizabeth Gaskell's Victorian novel, exploring industrialization, class divide, and the blossoming romance between Margaret Hale and John Thornton."
          },
          {
            "Question": "In 'Call the Midwife', what historical event shapes the midwifery practice in London's East End?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Baby Boom",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Plague Outbreak",
              "World War II",
              "Great Fire of London"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The series intertwines the compassionate midwifery experiences, amidst the post-war baby boom, encapsulating the evolving societal dynamics in London's East End."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which celebrated architect's career is spotlighted in the TV series 'The Architect of Cologne'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Richard Neutra",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Le Corbusier",
              "Frank Lloyd Wright",
              "Ludwig Mies van der Rohe"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Architect of Cologne' explores the influential legacy of architect Richard Neutra, known for his modernist designs and impact on urban development."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the prominent figure at the center of the TV series 'Versailles'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Louis XIV",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Napoleon Bonaparte",
              "Catherine de' Medici",
              "Henry IV"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The captivating series delves into the reign of the Sun King, Louis XIV, and the grandeur, court intrigues, and political maneuverings within the opulent Palace of Versailles."
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  ]
}